Finding Aid for Claude Thomas Stoner Photographs and Papers 1870s-1977
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Unclassified Photographs
  - Miscellaneous
    - Locomotives (line unidentified)
      - Fontaine engine (Box 2)
      - Streamline engine (Box 2)
      - Two engines (MTRR?) in lumber yard (Box 2)
    - Rail cars
      - Baggage car (Box 2)
      - Hand car and crew, 4 photographs (Box 2)
      - Passenger car, 3 photographs (Box 2)
      - Special car (Box 2)
    - Various railroad topics
      - Bridge, 4 photographs (Box 2)
      - Car interior (Box 2)
      - Pike's Peak plaque (Box 2)
      - Shops exterior (Box 2)
      - Shops interior (Box 2)
      - Station (Box 2)
      - Switch equipment(?) (Box 2)
      - Track repair (Box 2)
      - Winter scene (Box 2)
      - Wreck, 2 photographs (Box 2)
    - Non-railroad topics
      - Family in front of cobblestone house (Box 2)
      - Portrait of unidentified man (Box 2)
      - Steam tractor (Box 2)
      - Stoner late in life, 2 photographs (Box 2)
      - Photocopies of family photos (Box 2)
- Photograph Albums
  The Albums series (Box 3) contains one series of albums from the Detroit River Tunnel Company and one album from the Michigan Central Railroad. Other photos from the Detroit River Tunnel Company that were once part of an album are found in the Unclassified photos series. Photos in this series are indexed by railroad name and topic.
  - Detroit River Tunnel Co.: Progress pictures
    (chiefly photos of excavation of Detroit, Mich., open cut, construction of tunnel sections, and river dredging)
    - May 15, 1907 (Box 3)
    - June 15 1907 (Box 3)
    - July 1, 1907 (Box 3)
    - July 15, 1907 (Box 3)
    - August 1, 1907 (Box 3)
    - August 15, 1907 (Box 3)
    - September 15, 1907 (Box 3)
    - October 1, 1907 (Box 3)
    - November 1, 1907 (Box 3)
    - November 15, 1907 (Box 3)
    - May 1, 1908 (Box 3)
    - May 15, 1908 (Box 3)
    - June 1, 1908 (Box 3)
    - June 15, 1908 (Box 3)
    - July 1, 1908 (Box 3)
    - July 15, 1908 (Box 3)
    - August 1, 1908 (Box 3)
    - August 15, 1908 (Box 3)
    - Undated 1907-1908 (Box 3)
  - Michigan Central
    - Photos of track construction between Oshtemo and Mattawan, Mich. (Box 3)
- Unclassified Negatives
  The Unclassified negatives series (Boxes 4-5) contains negatives that Stoner did not add to his main classified series. Prints for a few of these negatives are found in the Unclassified prints series. The negatives are arranged alphabetically by the name of the railroad represented. These negatives are generally not well identified. Negatives in this series are indexed by railroad name and topic. Unless otherwise noted, the collection contains only a negative of each item; note that the numbering sequences are incomplete and overlapping
  - Ann Arbor Railroad
    - Engine 121 (Box 4)
    - Diesel engine 55 (Box 4)
    - Carferry no. 6, Frankfort, Mich. (Box 4)
    - Carferry Wabash, Frankfort, Mich. (Box 4)
      (no. 3; print available)
    - Carferries, Frankfort, Mich. (Box 4)
      (no. 6-8)
    - Carferry no. 6, Frankfort, Mich. (Box 4)
    - Carferries, Frankfort, Mich. (Box 4)
      (no. 10-11)
    - Carferry (Box 4)
      (no. 12)
    - Carferry, Frankfort, Mich. (Box 4)
      (no. 13-14)
    - Carferry (Box 4)
      (no. 15)
    - Carferry, Frankfort, Mich. (Box 4)
      (no. 16)
    - Carferry (Box 4)
      (no. 17-18)
    - Carferry, Frankfort, Mich. (Box 4)
      (no. 19)
    - Foundered carferry interior, Manistique, Mich. (Box 4)
      (no. 15; print available)
    - Engine 1614 Durand, Mich. 1938 (Box 4)
      (no. 42-43)
    - Passengers waiting at depot, Howell, Mich. (Box 4)
      (no. 43)
    - Engine and passenger train after snowstorm, Ann Arbor, Mich. 1918 (Box 4)
      (no. 45; similar to AA152)
    - Huron River Bridge, Ann Arbor, Mich. 1971 (Box 4)
      (no. 1-2)
    - Engine 2173 (Box 4)
      (no. 7)
    - Engine 16--(unidentified) (Box 4)
    - Train wrecks (Box 4)
    - Ann Arbor, Mich. (Box 4)
    - Near Hamburg, Mich. 1908 (Box 4)
  - Ann Arbor Street Railway
    - Street car in front of Ann Arbor Savings Bank (Box 4)
  - Baltimore & Ohio
    - "Crab" type engine (Box 4)
  - Boyne City & Southeastern
    - Engine 2 (Box 4)
  - Boyne City Railroad
    - Cars (Box 4)
    - Engine (Box 4)
    - Engine and shed (Box 4)
    - Engine 6 (Box 4)
    - Engine 11 (Box 4)
    - Engine 18 (Box 4)
    - Engine 18 and station, Boyne Falls, Mich. (Box 4)
    - Old track line(?) (Box 4)
  - Cass Scenic Railroad
    - Shay engine 1972 (Box 4)
    - Shay engines 4 and 5 1972 (Box 4)
      (no. 2-4)
    - Track 1972 (Box 4)
      (no. 5)
    - Shay engines 2 and 3 1972 (Box 4)
      (no. 6-7)
    - Shay engines 4 and 5 1972 (Box 4)
      (no. 8-9)
    - Shay engines 2, 3, 4, and 5 1972 (Box 4)
    - Shay engines 4 and 5 1972 (Box 4)
      (no. 12-14)
    - Shay engine 3 1973 (Box 4)
      (no. 1A)
    - Shay engine 6 1973 (Box 4)
      (no. 2A)
    - Engine 1973 (Box 4)
      (no. 3A)
    - Train 1973 (Box 4)
      (no. 4A)
    - Shay engine 5 1973 (Box 4)
      (no. 5A-6A)
  - Chesapeake & Ohio
    - Engine 2736 (Box 4)
    - Engine 1225 (Box 4)
    - Engine 1245 (Box 4)
  - Chicago & West Michigan
    - Engine 16 (Box 4)
  - Chicago, Kalamazoo & Saginaw
    - Freight car (Box 4)
  - Croton Dam, Croton, Mich.
    - Views (Box 4)
  - Cummer Sons Cypress
    - Engine 5 at museum (Box 4)
    - Log loader 1961 (Box 4)
      (no. 28; print available)
    - Mill, Lacoochee, Fla. 1961 (Box 4)
      (no. 29; print available)
  - Detroit & Toledo Shore Line
    - Engine 27, Durand, Mich. 1935 (Box 4)
  - Duluth, South Shore & Atlantic
    - Engine 3 at Soo Centennial 1955 (Box 4)
  - East Broad Top
    - Roundhouse (Box 4)
    - Train and station (Box 4)
    - Train (Box 4)
    - Engine 12 (Box 4)
    - Train (Box 4)
    - Engine 12 (Box 4)
      (no. 7-9)
    - Train (Box 4)
  - East Jordan & Southern
    - Engine 6 in park, East Jordan, Mich. (Box 4)
  - Escanaba & Lake Superior
    - Snow plow (Box 4)
  - Famous engines and trains
    - Concord Coach (Box 4)
    - Engine Genoa (Box 4)
    - Military engine, 20th century (Box 4)
  - Flint & Pere Marquette
    - Steamer no. 3, Manistee, Mich. (Box 4)
  - Forest Products Chemical Co.
    - Engine 2 (Box 4)
  - Frankfort, Mich., views
    - Town and mills (Box 4)
      (no. 1; print available)
    - Ruins of Hotel Frontenac (Box 4)
      (no. 2; print available)
    - Ship's crew (Box 4)
    - Life saving drill (Box 4)
      (no. 4-6; print available)
    - Log drive (Box 4)
      (no. 7; print available)
    - Town and rural area (Box 4)
      (no. 8; print available)
    - Steamer in front of Hotel Frontenac (Box 4)
      (no. 9; print available)
    - Schooner (Box 4)
      (no. 10; print available)
    - Steamer in harbor (Box 4)
      (no. 11; print available)
    - Life saving crew (Box 4)
      (no. 12; print available)
    - Motorboat Gotland (Box 4)
      (no. 13; print available)
    - Construction (?) (Box 4)
      (no. 14; print available)
    - Harbor view (Box 4)
      (no. 16-17)
  - Goldrush Junction
    - Engine no. 1 (Box 4)
  - Goldrush-Pigeon Forge, Gatlinburg & Western
    - Engine 92 (Box 4)
  - Grand Trunk Western
    - Engine 6407 (Box 4)
    - Station scene (Box 4)
    - Unidentified train (Box 4)
      (no. 3-4)
    - Engine 2452 in yard (Box 4)
    - Engine 3750 (Box 4)
      (no. 6,8)
    - Engine 3405 Battle Creek, Mich. 1934 (Box 4)
    - Engine 3524 Battle Creek, Mich. 1934 (Box 4)
    - Engine 3439 Battle Creek, Mich. 1934 (Box 4)
    - Engine 692, Battle Creek, Mich. 1934 (Box 4)
    - Engine 2670 Durand, Mich. 1935 (Box 4)
    - Engine 6306 Battle Creek, Mich. 1936 (Box 4)
    - Engine 3756 Durand, Mich. 1935 (Box 4)
      (no. 8)
    - Engine 6040 Durand, Mich. 1936 (Box 4)
    - Engine 5046 Durand, Mich. 1936 (Box 4)
      (no. 11)
    - Engine 5034 Durand, Mich. 1936 (Box 4)
    - Engine 5038 Durand, Mich. 1937 (Box 4)
    - Engine 5031 Durand, Mich. 1937 (Box 4)
      (no. 14)
    - Engine 5048 Durand, Mich. 1937 (Box 4)
    - Engine 8343 Durand, Mich. 1937 (Box 4)
    - Engine 8302 Durand, Mich. 1937 (Box 4)
      (no. 17)
    - Engine 3443 Battle Creek, Mich. 1934 (Box 4)
    - Engine 3434 Battle Creek, Mich. 1934 (Box 4)
    - Engine 3518 Battle Creek, Mich. 1934 (Box 4)
      (no. 20)
    - Engine 3719 Battle Creek, Mich. 1934 (Box 4)
      (no. 21)
    - Engine 3729 Battle Creek, Mich. 1934 (Box 4)
      (no. 22)
    - Engine 3711 Battle Creek, Mich. 1934 (Box 4)
      (no. 23)
    - Engine 3734 Battle Creek, Mich. 1934 (Box 4)
    - Engine 2677 Battle Creek, Mich. 1934 (Box 4)
      (no. 25)
    - Engine 5633 Battle Creek, Mich. 1934 (Box 4)
      (no. 26)
    - Engine 2684 Battle Creek, Mich. 1934 (Box 4)
      (no. 27)
    - Engine 5633 Belleview, Mich. 1930 (Box 4)
      (no. 28)
    - Engine 5633 Battle Creek, Mich. 1934 (Box 4)
      (no. 29)
    - Engine 5633 Belleview, Mich. 1934 (Box 4)
    - Engine 702, Battle Creek, Mich. 1934 (Box 4)
    - Engine 678, Battle Creek, Mich. 1934 (Box 4)
    - Engine 703, Battle Creek, Mich. 1934 (Box 4)
      (no. 33)
    - Engine 7475 Battle Creek, Mich. 1934 (Box 4)
      (no. 34)
    - Engine 7210 Battle Creek, Mich. 1934 (Box 4)
      (no. 35)
    - Engine 7206 Battle Creek, Mich. 1934 (Box 4)
      (no. 36)
    - Engine 8314 Battle Creek, Mich. 1934 (Box 4)
    - Engine 8349 Battle Creek, Mich. 1934 (Box 4)
      (no. 38)
    - Engine 5609 Lansing, Mich. 1937 (Box 4)
      (no. 39)
    - Engine 3749 Lansing, Mich. 1937 (Box 4)
      (no. 40)
    - Engine 7526 Lansing, Mich. 1936 (Box 4)
      (no. 41)
    - Engine 4079 Durand, Mich. 1961 (Box 4)
      (no. 48)
    - Engine 5627 Durand, Mich. 1961 (Box 4)
    - Engine 6323 Durand, Mich. 1962 (Box 4)
      (no. 50)
    - Depot, Durand, Mich. 1962 (Box 4)
      (no. 51)
    - Michigan Railroad Club train (Box 4)
    - Engine 6323 and Michigan Railroad Club train (Box 4)
    - Michigan Railroad Club train (Box 4)
    - Engine 5043 Durand, Mich. (Box 4)
    - Engine 5632 on display, Durand, Mich. (Box 4)
    - Engine 6319, Durand, Mich. (Box 4)
    - Engine 5043 and other engines, Durand, Mich. (Box 4)
  - High bridge
    - Views 1950 (Box 4)
      (no. 1-3)
    - Views (Box 4)
      (no. 41-42)
  - Hobart & Manistee River
    - Engine and loggers (Box 4)
  - Jennings, Mich., views
    - Chemical plant (Box 4)
  - Lake Shore & Michigan Southern
    - Train and interurban on bridge, Sandusky, Ohio (Box 4)
  - Logging and logging railroads
    - Stratford, Mich., plaque (Box 4)
    - Log jam (Box 4)
    - Logging camp (Box 4)
    - Sawmill (Box 4)
    - Lumber storage (Box 4)
    - Logging scene (Box 4)
      (no. 6)
    - Sawmill (Box 4)
    - Loggers (Box 4)
    - Two engines (Box 4)
    - Log train at rollway (Box 4)
    - Engine and crew (Box 4)
    - Logging camp (Box 4)
      (no. 12-13)
    - Loading a log train (Box 4)
    - Logging camp (Box 4)
      (no. 15-16)
    - Sawmill (Box 4)
    - Sawmill and engine (Box 4)
    - Log train (Box 4)
    - Mill under construction (Box 4)
    - Sawmill (Box 4)
    - Sawmill, 3 negatives (Box 4)
    - Lumber storage, glass negative (Box 4)
  - Louisville, New Albany & Corydon
    - Engine 5 (Box 4)
  - McKeen Motor Car Co.
    - Motor cars en route to Sacramento, Calif. 1908 (Box 4)
      (no. 9A)
    - Carbody used as diner (Box 4)
  - Mammoth Cave Railroad
    - Engine and car (Box 4)
  - Manistique & Lake Superior
    - Engine 2390 ready for scrapping, Owosso, Mich. (Box 4)
      (no. 52)
  - Mid-Continent Railway Museum, Wis.
    - Miniature train 1971 (Box 4)
    - Train and station 1971 (Box 4)
    - Miniature train (Box 4)
    - Engine 2 1971 (Box 4)
    - Shop buildings 1971 (Box 4)
  - Miniature and model trains
    - Unidentified (Box 4)
      (no. 1-6)
    - Pere Marquette Jr. (Box 4)
  - National Railroad Museum, Green Bay, Wis.
    - Milwaukee Road(?) Engine 261 (Box 4)
    - Engine 101 (Box 4)
    - Chesapeake & Ohio Engine 2736 (Box 4)
    - Santa Fe Engine 5017 (Box 4)
    - Milwaukee Road(?) Engine 261 (Box 4)
    - British Railways Engine 60008 (Box 4)
    - C.W. Jones Lumber Co. crawler tractor (Box 4)
    - Union Pacific Engine 4017 (Box 4)
    - British Railways Engine 60008 plaque (Box 4)
    - Engine 508 (Box 4)
    - Union Pacific Engine 4017 (Box 4)
    - Union Pacific Engine 4017 plaque (Box 4)
    - Engine 29 and train (Box 4)
    - Soo Line Engine 2718 (Box 4)
    - Station and trains (Box 4)
    - Miniature engine (Box 4)
    - Rock Island Engine (Box 4)
  - New York Central
    - Engine 5445 (Box 4)
    - Large press on flatcar (Box 4)
      (no. 2-6)
    - Shay engine 1899 (Box 4)
    - Engine 5005 crossing bridge (Box 4)
    - Engine 2065 Lansing, Mich. 1938 (Box 4)
      (no. 44)
    - Engine 6944 Lansing, Mich. 1938 (Box 4)
      (no. 45)
    - Engine 6933 Lansing, Mich. 1938 (Box 4)
      (no. 46)
    - Engine 886, Lansing, Mich. 1938 (Box 4)
      (no. 47)
    - Diesel engine 4001 Ann Arbor, Mich. (Box 4)
    - Train at Barton Pond Bridge, Ann Arbor, Mich. (Box 4)
      (no. 47, 53)
  - New York Central & Hudson River
    - Engine 999 (Box 4)
  - New York, Chicago & St., Louis
    - Engine 170 (Box 4)
      (no. 22; print available)
  - Norfolk & Western
    - Engine 578 (Box 4)
  - Pere Marquette
    - Collision (Box 4)
    - Engine 917 (Box 4)
    - Engine 298 (Box 4)
    - Engine 917 (Box 4)
      (no. 4; print available)
    - Diesel engine 102 at station, Howell, Mich. (Box 4)
    - Diesel engine 103 (Box 4)
    - Carferries, including No. 21, Ludington, Mich. (Box 4)
  - Ohio Railway Museum
    - Engine 2 (Box 4)
  - Portland Co.
    - P&K Railroad engine (Box 4)
    - P&O Railroad Engine 6 (Box 4)
    - Engine 476 (Box 4)
    - PS&P Railroad Engine 12 (Box 4)
  - Railroad stations
    - Hawk Junction, Ont. (Box 4)
    - Benton Harbor, Mich., Union Depot (Box 4)
    - Lake City, Mich. (Box 4)
      (no. 5-7)
    - Warsaw, Ind., Big Four depot (Box 4)
    - Goshen, Ind., Big Four depot (Box 4)
    - Thompsonville, Mich. (Box 4)
    - Howell, Mich. (Box 4)
    - Adrian, Mich., plaque (Box 4)
    - Hudson, Mich. (Box 4)
    - Unidentified (Box 4)
      (no. 6, 46, and unnumbered)
  - Saginaw Southern
    - Engine 585 (Box 4)
  - Shay
    - Loading lumber schooner (Box 4)
    - People (Box 4)
      (no. 2-3)
    - Shay house and auto (Box 4)
    - Portrait (Box 4)
      (no. 5-9)
    - Shay house and auto (Box 4)
    - Shay house (Box 4)
      (no. 11-13)
    - Shay yacht, Aha (Box 4)
    - Patent drawing (Box 4)
    - Specifications (Box 4)
    - Shay engine (Box 4)
    - Shay engine and log train (Box 4)
  - Ships
    - Freighters in St. Clair River(?) (Box 4)
  - Soo Line
    - Engine 730 (Box 4)
  - Street railroads
    - Lansing & Page Ave. Car 571 (Box 4)
  - Time schedules
    - Albany & Buffalo 1843 (Box 4)
    - Abraham Lincoln funeral train (Box 4)
  - Train wrecks
    - Unidentified (Box 4)
      (no. 4-5)
    - Engine 809 (Box 4)
    - Chelsea, Mich. 1918 (Box 4)
    - Northville, Mich. 1907 (Box 4)
    - Engine 31 (Box 4)
    - Unidentified (Box 4)
      (no. 2, 4-5)
    - Train wrecked in snow (Box 4)
  - Tweetsie Railroad
    - Train and buildings (Box 4)
    - Engine 12 (Box 4)
    - Engine 190 and train on bridge (Box 4)
    - Engine 190 and train at station (Box 4)
    - Engine 190 (Box 4)
  - Uintah Railway
    - Engine (Box 4)
  - Union Pacific
    - Snow removal machine competition 1890 (Box 4)
      (no. 1-3; prints available)
    - Engine 4017 (Box 4)
    - Engine 58, Ann Arbor, Mich., Michigan Central depot (Box 4)
  - Wabash
    - Engine 2257 (Box 4)
    - Engine 2201 (Box 4)
    - Engine 2209 (Box 4)
    - Engine 2257 (Box 4)
      (no. 5; print available)
  - Welding rail joints
    (no. 1-8)
    - Western & Atlantic (Box 4)
    - Engine General (Box 4)
      (no. 2, 14)
    - Engine General, cut from magazine (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Locomotives (line unidentified)
      - Engine 409 and tank car, Boulder (Colo.?) 1902 (Box 5)
      - Engine (Box 5)
        (no. 5-10)
      - Engine 4 (Box 5)
      - Miniature Engine 606 (Box 5)
      - Engine 1202 (Box 5)
      - Engine (Box 5)
        (no. 23-26)
      - Engine 5 (Box 5)
        (no. 27-29)
      - Engine (Box 5)
      - Engine 506 (Box 5)
      - Engine Antwerp (RW&O) (Box 5)
        (no. 9B)
      - Engine 5 (Box 5)
        (no. 26-26A)
      - Miniature Engine 606, Fair trip 1954 (Box 5)
      - Engine (Box 5)
        (no 37)
      - Engine 9618 and crew (Box 5)
      - Engine 25 (Box 5)
      - Engine 14 (Box 5)
      - Engine Campos Garangol (Box 5)
      - Engine (Box 5)
    - Rail cars
      - Car 5012 (Box 5)
      - Streetcars (Box 5)
      - Car 5012 and streetcars (Box 5)
    - Various railroad topics
      - Loading carferry (Box 5)
      - Bridge, Sidney (Box 5)
      - Railyard, Lima (?) (Box 5)
      - Railfan scene (Box 5)
      - Water tower (Box 5)
      - Fair trip 1954 (Box 5)
        (no. 30-31)
      - Train, Fair trip 1954 (Box 5)
      - Station, Fair trip 1954 (Box 5)
        (no. 34-35)
      - Unidentified railroad worker (Box 5)
      - Railroad museum (Box 5)
      - Train (Box 5)
        (no. 11, 13-14)
      - Shops (Box 5)
      - Train (Box 5)
        (no. 19, 30-31)
      - Train in flood (Box 5)
      - Workmen in snow (Box 5)
      - Train in snow 1947 (Box 5)
      - Train in snow (Box 5)
    - Non-railroad topics
      - Marquette's death, plaque (Box 5)
      - Sharon Mills, Mich. (Box 5)
      - Threshing rig near Durand, Mich. 1958 (Box 5)
      - Plow (Box 5)
      - Steam tractor (Box 5)
      - Tree (Box 5)
      - Addison, Mich., building (Box 5)
      - Unidentified aerial photo (Box 5)
      - Portable sawmill (Box 5)
      - Mill (Box 5)
        (no. 20-21)
      - Building with dome (Box 5)
      - Interior of dome (Box 5)
      - Farmer's Telephone Co. office, Grass Lake, Mich. (Box 5)
      - 1903 Olds auto on trailer (Box 5)
        (no. 54)
      - 40 et 8 Society French engine in parade, Howell, Mich. (Box 5)
      - Steam tractor (Box 5)
      - Hunting party (Box 5)
        (4 negatives)
      - Family with ox cart (Box 5)
      - Woman (Box 5)
      - Group of men (Box 5)
- Papers
  The Papers series (Boxes 6-7) contains correspondence and collected materials relating to Stoner's photograph collection and to Michigan railroads in general. Stoner corresponded with other collectors of railroad photos, with sources of photos, and with people purchasing copies of his photos. The correspondence sometimes provides identifying information and context for photos in the collection, but it would be difficult to locate information about any specific photo in the correspondence. This series also contains miscellaneous collected materials, both manuscript and printed, about Michigan railroads.
  - Biographical (Box 6)
  - Correspondence 1953-1977
    - By correspondent A-Z, 13 folders (Box 6)
    - Cairns, F.D. (Box 6)
    - Harvey, Harold L. (Box 6)
    - Hauck, Cornelius W. (Box 6)
    - Hirzel, Fred C., 5 folders (Box 6)
    - Koch, Michael, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Smarey, K. Gus, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Subject files
    - Ann Arbor Railroad, 3 folders (Box 6)
      (includes locomotive rosters and timetables)
    - Chesapeake & Ohio Historical Society (Box 6)
    - Grand Trunk, 3 folders (Box 7)
    - Locomotive rosters, Miscellaneous, 3 folders (Box 7)
    - Logging railroads (Box 7)
    - McKeen Motor Car Co. (Box 7)
    - Manistee & North Eastern (Box 7)
    - Michigan Central (Box 7)
    - Pere Marquette (Box 7)
    - Shay, Ephraim (Box 7)
    - Timetables, Miscellaneous (Box 7)
    - Wabash (Box 7)
    - Wells Fargo (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 7)
  - Classified negatives, Sleeve descriptions, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Photo log (Box 7)
  - Printed materials 1840, 1910s-1960s, 5 folders (Box 7)
  - Clippings 1940s-1970s, undated, 6 folders (Box 7)
- Classified Negatives
  [Staff Use Only]
  The Classified negatives series (Boxes 8-12) contains negatives for all the items in the Classified photos series. This series is not open for researcher use, and may be used only by staff members for the purpose of making copy prints.
  - Code AA-CPR (Box 8)
  - Code CWM-GTR (Box 9)
  - Code GTW-LR (Box 10)
  - Code LS1-P20 (Box 11)
  - Code P21-X (Box 12)
- Duplicate Material
  The Duplicate material series (Box 13) contains two types of photos: original prints (and some glass negatives) of photos represented in the Classified photos series, and duplicate copy prints of photos represented in either the Classified photos or Unclassified photos series. This series is not open for researcher use. The first group of photos may be used by staff if needed to create new copy negatives. The second may be used for display or other purposes.
  - Original prints (or negatives) of classified photos
    - AA3 (Box 13)
    - AA12 (Box 13)
    - AA15-16 (Box 13)
    - AA25 (Box 13)
    - AA27 (Box 13)
    - AA31-32 (Box 13)
      (glass negatives)
    - AA71 (Box 13)
    - AA81-84 (Box 13)
    - AA85 (Box 13)
      (glass negative)
    - AA93 (Box 13)
    - AA98-99 (Box 13)
    - AA106-107 (Box 13)
    - AA118-124 (Box 13)
    - AA156 (Box 13)
    - AA187-188 (Box 13)
    - BA1 (Box 13)
    - CC1 (Box 13)
    - CJ1 (Box 13)
    - CWM1 (Box 13)
    - CWM1-2 (Box 13)
    - CWM3 (Box 13)
    - DLN1-2 (Box 13)
    - DLN8 (Box 13)
    - DM1 (Box 13)
    - DM4 (Box 13)
    - ELS3 (Box 13)
    - FPM4 (Box 13)
    - FSE7 (Box 13)
    - FSE9 (Box 13)
      (2 glass negatives, both similar but not identical to FSE9)
    - GRI3 (Box 13)
    - GTR14 (Box 13)
    - GTR72 (Box 13)
    - GTR83-84 (Box 13)
    - IR5 (Box 13)
    - LR2-3 (Box 13)
    - LR19 (Box 13)
    - LR23 (Box 13)
    - LR76 (Box 13)
    - LR91 (Box 13)
    - LR185 (Box 13)
    - LSMS12 (Box 13)
    - LSMS15 (Box 13)
    - MC1 (Box 13)
    - MC1-2 (Box 13)
    - MC4-5 (Box 13)
    - MC34 (Box 13)
    - MNE4 (Box 13)
    - MNE13 (Box 13)
    - MNE13 (Box 13)
    - MRY1 (Box 13)
    - MSE1-2 (Box 13)
    - OCT1 (Box 13)
    - PM5 (Box 13)
    - PM16-17 (Box 13)
    - PM18 (Box 13)
    - PM42 (Box 13)
    - PM105 (Box 13)
      (same as LR185)
    - PM106 (Box 13)
  - Duplicate copy prints, 3 folders (Box 13)
    unsorted
  - Duplicate copy negatives (Box 13)
Index to railroads and company names
The letter/number code following each heading refers to Stoner's system for identifying his collection of railroad negatives. Descriptions of the images will be found in the Classified Photograph series.
Addis, Wm. T. -- (see Spring Harbor Railroad)
Albany & Buffalo -- see unclassified negatives under Time schedules
Alley, J. -- see J. Alley & Co.
Alpena & Hubbard Lake -- LR112
American Rolling Mills -- CLC7-8
American Telegraph Co. -- P32
Ann Arbor & Ypsilanti Electric Railway -- AAY1-5
Ann Arbor Railroad -- AA1-263, P1-9, P45, TT1, also unclassified photos under Ann Arbor Railroad and Railroad stations and unclassified negatives under Ann Arbor Railroad; see also its predecessor Toledo, Ann Arbor, and North Michigan
Ann Arbor Street Railway -- AASR1-5, also unclassified photos and unclassified negatives under this name
Antrim Iron Co. -- LR47, LR74, LR121
Arcadia & Betsey River -- ABR1-12
Atchison, Topeka & Santa Fe -- see unclassified photos under Atchison, Topeka & Santa Fe and unclassified negatives under National Railroad Museum
Atlantic & Gulf -- AG1-2, also unclassified photos under Famous engines and trains
Au Sable & Northwestern -- DM9
Also unclassified photos under this name; see also its predecessor J.E. Potts Salt & Lumber Co. and its successor Detroit & Mackinac
Backus, G. & J. -- see G. & J. Backus
Baltimore & Ohio -- see unclassified photos and unclassified negatives under this name
Bath & Hammondsport -- RM2-3
Bay de Noquet Lumber Co. -- see Nahma & Northern
Bear Lake & Eastern -- LR23-25, LR76, LR133, LR218-219